<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>minimalism on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/minimalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in minimalism on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/minimalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sound of Silence: A Digital Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/soundofsilencedigitalinterpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/soundofsilencedigitalinterpretation/</guid>
      <description>This week I listened to the Sound of Silence by Simon and Garfunkel. Recorded in 1966 the song uses strong imagery of light and darkness to describe how peoples ignorance and apathy was destroying their ability to communicate with one another. Interestingly, if released today, the lyrics could equally be interpreted to describe how our misuse of some technologies is deeply impacting the very fabric of society. Here is my digital interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce your Digital Footprints to improve Privacy</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/reduce-your-digital-footprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/reduce-your-digital-footprints/</guid>
      <description>This week I have been teaching one of my favourite topics Social Engineering. If you are not familiar with the topic, social engineering is the act of abusing human psychology to take advantage of a persons natural tendencies and emotional reactions in order to trick then into making security mistakes or giving away sensitive information.
As part of the series we also explored open source intelligence (OSINT) which is a method often used by hackers to collect information from public sources in order to build a detailed profile about a victim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Minimalism: How to be more intentional with technology</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/digital-minimalism-how-to-be-more-intentional-with-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/digital-minimalism-how-to-be-more-intentional-with-technology/</guid>
      <description>Digital Minimalism is possibly a term you have never heard before. Perhaps, like me you only recently heard the term and let out a slight groan, conflating the idea with the wider, more popular trending philosophy of Minimalism, in which people live a life with less stuff (I’m minimalising the philosophy there).
Let me clear, I like the idea of Minimalism. I have even tried to adopt some principles in my life, although all attempts have ended in failure as we are a family of hoarders.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
