<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:43:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of attack and defense</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-psychology-of-attack-and-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:43:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-psychology-of-attack-and-defense/</guid>
      <description>A fascinating video by Perry Carpenter about the Psychology of attack and defense.
  In the video Perry explains the art and science behind deception. Also, how threat actors use this knowledge to exploit vulnerabilities in human psychology to target end-users and how security awareness training can help users spot deception. A great watch to better understand social engineering scams, disinformation campaigns, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Security Matters</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</guid>
      <description>We all know (hopefully) we should take security seriously. Indeed, the frequency and impact of security threats continue to evolve, with new threats emerging almost daily. We also have to acknowledge that we live in a highly connected world using technology and the Internet daily to gather information from websites, collaborate on projects, connect remote employees to company networks, or utilise cloud platforms to do business. Each of the activities exposes us to some element of risk, therefore, it is fair to say that completely avoiding risk is probably impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
