<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 19:43:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switch to Linux for better privacy?</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/switch_to_linux_for_better_privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 19:43:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/switch_to_linux_for_better_privacy/</guid>
      <description>I am a long time user and advocate of Linux. I use it daily in my teaching, and have long expounded the many security and privacy benefits that come from using the operating systems.
The problem is, for the average user, it can be daunting thought to make the switch. Despite, this I would encourage you to watch this video by Rob Braxman. In it, he fully explains the underlying structure of Linux, namely the mainline Kernel and GNU utilities built on top of it, leading to the many distributions to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of attack and defence</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-psychology-of-attack-and-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 19:43:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-psychology-of-attack-and-defence/</guid>
      <description>A fascinating video by Perry Carpenter about the Psychology of attack and defence In the video Perry explains the art and science behind deception. Also, how threat actors use this knowledge to exploit vulnerabilities in human psychology to target end-users and how security awareness training can help users spot deception.
A great watch to better understand social engineering, scams, disinformation campaigns, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you leaking your Social Media Fingerprint?</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/social-media-fingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:43:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/social-media-fingerprint/</guid>
      <description>There is a well known vulnerability in many web platforms that allows a potential attacker to determine the online platforms you are signed up to and are currently logged into. The exploit is pretty simple and actually easy to fix, however, most companies have not bothered to fix it because it does pose a serious risk to their platforms. It does pose a potential issue for our privacy so let&amp;rsquo;s briefly look at how we can protect ourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Sidewalk: Is it safe or should I opt out</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/amazonsidewalkprivacyconcerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/amazonsidewalkprivacyconcerns/</guid>
      <description>Amazon recently announced the launch of a new service: Amazon Sidewalk which appears to have caused quite a stir. The tech giant has come under fire for the way it has rolled out the new service, amid concerns regarding user privacy and security.
Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly review the service to decide whether it is a useful new feature or a cause for concern.
What is Amazon Sidewalk? The first thing to note is that at present the service has only launched in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it safe to use a browser&#39;s built-in password manager</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting article about Password Managers written by Tavis Ormandy, a well known researcher working on Google’s Zero-Day project. The article considered whether it is better to use the intrinsic password manager already built-in to your web browser (most web browsers now offer to save your passwords) or to use an extrinsic third-party app like Bitwarden .
Let&amp;rsquo;s review the arguments he presented in his article and determine if it is safe to use a browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in password manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teens, Tech and Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/teenstechandmentalhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/teenstechandmentalhealth/</guid>
      <description>The Oxford Internet Institute (University of Oxford) published the findings of a study this week which investigated the impact of technology on mental health in adolescents.
The study investigated engagement with smartphones, social media and television and reported finding little evidence to suggest an increased association between technology use and mental health exists.
I found these findings somewhat surprising so decided to dig a little deeper.
Firstly, information about new digital media has only been collected for a relatively short time, therefore, drawing firm conclusions about the impact on mental health at this stage may be premature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound of Silence: A Digital Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/soundofsilencedigitalinterpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/soundofsilencedigitalinterpretation/</guid>
      <description>This week I listened to the Sound of Silence by Simon and Garfunkel. Recorded in 1966 the song uses strong imagery of light and darkness to describe how peoples ignorance and apathy was destroying their ability to communicate with one another. Interestingly, if released today, the lyrics could equally be interpreted to describe how our misuse of some technologies is deeply impacting the very fabric of society. Here is my digital interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce your Digital Footprints to improve Privacy</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/reduce-your-digital-footprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/reduce-your-digital-footprints/</guid>
      <description>This week I have been teaching one of my favourite topics Social Engineering. If you are not familiar with the topic, social engineering is the act of abusing human psychology to take advantage of a persons natural tendencies and emotional reactions in order to trick then into making security mistakes or giving away sensitive information.
As part of the series we also explored open source intelligence (OSINT) which is a method often used by hackers to collect information from public sources in order to build a detailed profile about a victim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Web Browser for Privacy in 2021</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 13:21:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Welcome A web browser can collect a lot of information about you. As the tool most used to browse the Internet, they can track the sites you visit, how long you spent on them, which links you clicked on or purchases you made, and much more. Choosing the right web browser is, therefore, an important consideration when trying to improve your online privacy.
Ideally, you should choose a web browser which blocks all trackers by default, or at least, allows you to easily configure it do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-factor Authentication 2FA and Biometrics</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/multi-factor-authentication-2fa-and-biometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/multi-factor-authentication-2fa-and-biometrics/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article, How to create and manage strong passwords, I demonstrated how using mnemonics to remember complex passwords or adopting a bitwarden can be used to improve your digital security, and make you a much more difficult target for potential hackers. It is, however, possible to protect your online digital interactions even further, by using Multi-factor authentication (MFA) to add extra layers of security when logging into systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antitrust: Tech Giants face Congress</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</guid>
      <description>Tech giants: Apple, Google, Facebook and Amazon were questioned by a US Congress subcommittee yesterday on issues relating to antitrust, and the suggestion they hold too much power. For nearly six hours, congress confronted the CEOs about whether they wielded their market power to eliminate competitors and amass huge data on their customers. Indeed, congressman David Cicilline summarised the hearing by suggesting:
Simply put, they have too much power. The firms have monopoly power, some need to be broken up, all need to be properly regulated and held accountable &amp;ndash; David Cicilline</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create and manage strong passwords</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/how-to-create-and-manage-strong-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/how-to-create-and-manage-strong-passwords/</guid>
      <description>We all know we should use secure passwords, but, how do you balance the necessity of highly secure passwords with the ability to easily recall them when needed? Depending on which study you read, the average person has 27 online accounts and between 70-80 passwords to remember. As a result, many people choose the path of least resistance (I’m working on a future post about this) so either use simple, easy to remember (and guess) passwords, or use the same password everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MindF*ck Inside Cambridge Analytica&#39;s Plot</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/minfckinsidecambridgeanalyticasplottobreaktheworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:31:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/minfckinsidecambridgeanalyticasplottobreaktheworld/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It seems an appropriate week to be talking about social media. Many advertisers and sponsors have suspended advertising on Facebook, and some big names have left twitter (they were banned to be fair) moving to it’s “anything goes” rival paler. What better week to share a review of Christopher Wylie’s book: Mindf*ck: Inside Cambridge Analytica’s Plot to Break the World.
Last week as I sat down to write a review I came across a great video on YouTube by Dan White , who kindly offered to share his review with subscribers of my mailing list (join the list to hear everything first).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DF Tube: How to watch YouTube distraction free</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/dftube-how-to-watch-youtube-distraction-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/dftube-how-to-watch-youtube-distraction-free/</guid>
      <description>YouTube is awesome. Who doesn’t like to watch cats and babies doing funny things, or learn how to replace a door catch on your dishwater to avoid an expensive plumbers bill. But, if you impulsively watch more and more videos and compulsively log in more frequently, even when you had planned to do something more productive, you may be addicted. In this article I will share some tips on how to avoid the black hole of YouTube using, amongst other things, DF Tube a plugin for Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our need for validation through Social Media</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/our-need-for-validation-through-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/our-need-for-validation-through-social-media/</guid>
      <description>So last week I took the plunge. I started my Blog and mailing list . It’s something I have been thinking about doing for a while, but always managed to find an excuse not to start, sound familiar ? This got me thinking about a quote I recently heard by Stoic philosopher, Epictetus:
If you want to improve, be content to be thought foolish and stupid - Epictetus
I think his point is that often the fear of looking foolish can cripple us and prevent us from starting a new venture or applying for a dream job or starting a blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The debate about Contact Tracing Apps</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-debate-about-contact-tracing-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/the-debate-about-contact-tracing-apps/</guid>
      <description>It appears the UK government have decided to scrap their NHS contact tracing app in favour of a model based on Google and Apple’s technology. In doing so, it joins a host of other countries (including Germany, Italy and Denmark) to favour a decentralised system developed by the Silicon Valley giants, rather than a centralised model developed locally. A step in the right direction ?
There has been much debate and concern about the need and function of contact tracing apps to fight the current global pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Facial Recognition</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/rethinking-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/rethinking-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>On the back of the horrific treatment of George Floyd a call for further measures to monitor police actions and increase accountability would not be unexpected. However, interestingly IBM, a leader in the provision of facial identification as a service, appear to be considering a rethink about how the technology should be used. CEO Arvind Krishna voiced support for a new bill aiming to reduce police violence, but called for a national dialogue about how/if the technology should be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Tech influence to grow post Covid</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/big-tech-influence-to-grow-post-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/big-tech-influence-to-grow-post-covid/</guid>
      <description>I probably don’t need to tell you the markets have been on a wild ride in the wake of the covid-19 outbreak. However, interestingly according to Forbes during this time, many of the same companies responsible for powering the recent decade-long bull market have gained even more clout, with tech behemoths Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Facebook and Microsoft now accounting for over 22% of the S&amp;amp;P. That’s up from a 15 % share in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the perfect tool or app exist?</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/does-the-perfect-tool-or-app-exits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/does-the-perfect-tool-or-app-exits/</guid>
      <description>If you are like me the search to find the perfect tool or app is never ending. Deep down I know it doesn’t exist, yet I look, convincing myself that If i can just find that perfect tool I will be more productive and save a lot of time. I am also aware that hunting for better tools is a distraction technique, but still I search. I often use a quote attributed to Abraham Lincoln to justify my actions…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Security Matters</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</guid>
      <description>We all know (hopefully) we should take security seriously. Indeed, the frequency and impact of security threats continue to evolve, with new threats emerging almost daily. We also have to acknowledge that we live in a highly connected world using technology and the Internet daily to gather information from websites, collaborate on projects, connect remote employees to company networks, or utilise cloud platforms to do business. Each of the activities exposes us to some element of risk, therefore, it is fair to say that completely avoiding risk is probably impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Privacy Matters</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-privacy-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-privacy-matters/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever stopped to think about the technology you use, or the online services you engage with on a regular basis ? Chances are you use some form of technology or internet service on a daily basis. If so, have you considered the increasing trust we are required to place in technology or companies to manage our daily interactions.
Whether it’s emails, holiday photos on social media, on-line shopping, internet banking or even health details; we are generating more personal data than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Minimalism: How to be more intentional with technology</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/digital-minimalism-how-to-be-more-intentional-with-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/digital-minimalism-how-to-be-more-intentional-with-technology/</guid>
      <description>Digital Minimalism is possibly a term you have never heard before. Perhaps, like me you only recently heard the term and let out a slight groan, conflating the idea with the wider, more popular trending philosophy of Minimalism, in which people live a life with less stuff (I’m minimalising the philosophy there).
Let me clear, I like the idea of Minimalism. I have even tried to adopt some principles in my life, although all attempts have ended in failure as we are a family of hoarders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Me in 10 seconds I am an author, scholar, and computer scientist whose work is focused at the intersection between humans and technology.
Outside of my academic life I write about societies increasing addiction to technology, and decreasing concern for privacy.
I love nature and the outdoors and spend most weekends on long walks or adventures with my family and dog.
Me in 10 minutes I am a computer scientist whose work primarily focuses on digital privacy and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inner Circle</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/innercircle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/innercircle/</guid>
      <description>During the Covid-19 lockdown, I started a weekly newsletter called McDermott Musings. You can sign up here In only a short space of time it has grown in popularity, with many readers saying it has really encouraged them to explore how to get a happier, healthier, and more productive relationship with technology.
Each week I send out a small exclusive email to subscribers. In this, I share some thoughts about subjects I’ve been pondering, along with tips on how to use technology better, and how to stay safe while maintaining your privacy online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>refine your digital interactions so they continue to support the goals and activities you want to pursue but minimise your exposure to risk and unhealthy relationships with technology
I believe we are at a crossroads. The Internet has brought about some fantastic innovations, however, in some cases technologies that were meant to liberate us have in fact exploited areas of human psychology, leaving many of us addicted to our phones, endlessly checking social media feeds, and comparing ourselves against the carefully curated digital versions of the people we follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Academia I am a researcher in Human-centred security. I seek to answer questions relating to security, privacy and trust at the intersection between humans and digital technologies, in particular the Internet. Current Research interests include, but are not limited to:
Areas of Interest Human Factors in Security:
Exploits against humans: Phishing, Social Engineering, Human Error; Cyber Psychology and Human Behaviour; Security by Design, Usability and Situational Awareness; Cybercrime. Machine Learning for Cybersecurity:</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
