<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 13:21:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Web Browser for Privacy in 2020</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 13:21:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>Welcome A web browser can collect a lot of information about you. As the tool most used to browse the Internet, they can track the sites you visit, how long you spent on them, which links you clicked on or purchases you made, and much more. Choosing the right web browser is, therefore, an important consideration when trying to improve your online privacy.
Ideally, you should choose a web browser which blocks all trackers by default, or at least, allows you to easily configure it do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antitrust: Tech Giants face Congress</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</guid>
      <description>Tech giants: Apple, Google, Facebook and Amazon were questioned by a US Congress subcommittee yesterday on issues relating to antitrust, and the suggestion they hold too much power. For nearly six hours, congress confronted the CEOs about whether they wielded their market power to eliminate competitors and amass huge data on their customers. Indeed, congressman David Cicilline summarised the hearing by suggesting:
 Simply put, they have too much power. The firms have monopoly power, some need to be broken up, all need to be properly regulated and held accountable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MindF*ck Inside Cambridge Analytica&#39;s Plot</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/minfckinsidecambridgeanalyticasplottobreaktheworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 22:31:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/minfckinsidecambridgeanalyticasplottobreaktheworld/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It seems an appropriate week to be talking about social media. Many advertisers and sponsors have suspended advertising on Facebook, and some big names have left twitter (they were banned to be fair) moving to it’s “anything goes” rival paler. What better week to share a review of Christopher Wylie’s book: Mindf*ck: Inside Cambridge Analytica’s Plot to Break the World.
Last week as I sat down to write a review I came across a great video on YouTube by Dan White , who kindly offered to share his review with subscribers of my mailing list (join the list to hear everything first).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
