<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.com/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is it safe to use a browser&#39;s built-in password manager</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting article about Password Managers written by Tavis Ormandy, a well known researcher working on Google’s Zero-Day project. The article considered whether it is better to use the intrinsic password manager already built-in to your web browser (most web browsers now offer to save your passwords) or to use an extrinsic third-party app like Bitwarden .
Let&amp;rsquo;s review the arguments he presented in his article and determine if it is safe to use a browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in password manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antitrust: Tech Giants face Congress</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/antitrust-tech-giants-face-congress/</guid>
      <description>Tech giants: Apple, Google, Facebook and Amazon were questioned by a US Congress subcommittee yesterday on issues relating to antitrust, and the suggestion they hold too much power. For nearly six hours, congress confronted the CEOs about whether they wielded their market power to eliminate competitors and amass huge data on their customers. Indeed, congressman David Cicilline summarised the hearing by suggesting:
 Simply put, they have too much power. The firms have monopoly power, some need to be broken up, all need to be properly regulated and held accountable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Security Matters</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/why-security-matters/</guid>
      <description>We all know (hopefully) we should take security seriously. Indeed, the frequency and impact of security threats continue to evolve, with new threats emerging almost daily. We also have to acknowledge that we live in a highly connected world using technology and the Internet daily to gather information from websites, collaborate on projects, connect remote employees to company networks, or utilise cloud platforms to do business. Each of the activities exposes us to some element of risk, therefore, it is fair to say that completely avoiding risk is probably impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
