<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social media on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social media on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.github.io/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teens, Tech and Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/teenstechandmentalhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/teenstechandmentalhealth/</guid>
      <description>The Oxford Internet Institute (University of Oxford) published the findings of a study this week which investigated the impact of technology on mental health in adolescents.
The study investigated engagement with smartphones, social media and television and reported finding little evidence to suggest an increased association between technology use and mental health exists.
I found these findings somewhat surprising so decided to dig a little deeper.
Firstly, information about new digital media has only been collected for a relatively short time, therefore, drawing firm conclusions about the impact on mental health at this stage may be premature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DF Tube: How to watch YouTube distraction free</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/dftube-how-to-watch-youtube-distraction-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/dftube-how-to-watch-youtube-distraction-free/</guid>
      <description>YouTube is awesome. Who doesn’t like to watch cats and babies doing funny things, or learn how to replace a door catch on your dishwater to avoid an expensive plumbers bill. But, if you impulsively watch more and more videos and compulsively log in more frequently, even when you had planned to do something more productive, you may be addicted. In this article I will share some tips on how to avoid the black hole of YouTube using, amongst other things, DF Tube a plugin for Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our need for validation through Social Media</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/our-need-for-validation-through-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/our-need-for-validation-through-social-media/</guid>
      <description>So last week I took the plunge. I started my Blog and mailing list . It’s something I have been thinking about doing for a while, but always managed to find an excuse not to start, sound familiar ? This got me thinking about a quote I recently heard by Stoic philosopher, Epictetus:
 If you want to improve, be content to be thought foolish and stupid - Epictetus
 I think his point is that often the fear of looking foolish can cripple us and prevent us from starting a new venture or applying for a dream job or starting a blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Privacy Matters</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/why-privacy-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.github.io/articles/why-privacy-matters/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever stopped to think about the technology you use, or the online services you engage with on a regular basis ? Chances are you use some form of technology or internet service on a daily basis. If so, have you considered the increasing trust we are required to place in technology or companies to manage our daily interactions.
Whether it’s emails, holiday photos on social media, on-line shopping, internet banking or even health details; we are generating more personal data than ever before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
