<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>protect on aRtFuL eNiGmA</title>
    <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/categories/protect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in protect on aRtFuL eNiGmA</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:43:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cdmcdermott.com/categories/protect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are you leaking your Social Media Fingerprint?</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/social-media-fingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 18:43:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/social-media-fingerprint/</guid>
      <description>There is a well known vulnerability in many web platforms that allows a potential attacker to determine the online platforms you are signed up to and are currently logged into. The exploit is pretty simple and actually easy to fix, however, most companies have not bothered to fix it because it does pose a serious risk to their platforms. It does pose a potential issue for our privacy so let&amp;rsquo;s briefly look at how we can protect ourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Sidewalk: Is it safe or should I opt out</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/amazonsidewalkprivacyconcerns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/amazonsidewalkprivacyconcerns/</guid>
      <description>Amazon recently announced the launch of a new service: Amazon Sidewalk which appears to have caused quite a stir. The tech giant has come under fire for the way it has rolled out the new service, amid concerns regarding user privacy and security.
Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly review the service to decide whether it is a useful new feature or a cause for concern.
 What is Amazon Sidewalk? The first thing to note is that at present the service has only launched in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it safe to use a browser&#39;s built-in password manager</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/browsersbuiltinpasswordmanager/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting article about Password Managers written by Tavis Ormandy, a well known researcher working on Google’s Zero-Day project. The article considered whether it is better to use the intrinsic password manager already built-in to your web browser (most web browsers now offer to save your passwords) or to use an extrinsic third-party app like Bitwarden .
Let&amp;rsquo;s review the arguments he presented in his article and determine if it is safe to use a browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in password manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Web Browser for Privacy in 2021</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 13:21:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/best-web-browser-for-privacy-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Welcome A web browser can collect a lot of information about you. As the tool most used to browse the Internet, they can track the sites you visit, how long you spent on them, which links you clicked on or purchases you made, and much more. Choosing the right web browser is, therefore, an important consideration when trying to improve your online privacy.
Ideally, you should choose a web browser which blocks all trackers by default, or at least, allows you to easily configure it do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-factor Authentication 2FA and Biometrics</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/multi-factor-authentication-2fa-and-biometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/multi-factor-authentication-2fa-and-biometrics/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article, How to create and manage strong passwords, I demonstrated how using mnemonics to remember complex passwords or adopting a bitwarden can be used to improve your digital security, and make you a much more difficult target for potential hackers. It is, however, possible to protect your online digital interactions even further, by using Multi-factor authentication (MFA) to add extra layers of security when logging into systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create and manage strong passwords</title>
      <link>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/how-to-create-and-manage-strong-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cdmcdermott.com/articles/how-to-create-and-manage-strong-passwords/</guid>
      <description>We all know we should use secure passwords, but, how do you balance the necessity of highly secure passwords with the ability to easily recall them when needed? Depending on which study you read, the average person has 27 online accounts and between 70-80 passwords to remember. As a result, many people choose the path of least resistance (I’m working on a future post about this) so either use simple, easy to remember (and guess) passwords, or use the same password everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
